Guide to the Ernst Thedore Stuhr Papers 1928-1956
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
Ernst Thedore Stuhr Papers
1928-1956
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center University Archives 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://osulibrary.oregonstate.edu/archives
MSS Stuhr
Stuhr, Ernst T. (Ernst Thedore), 1900-1980
0.5 cubic feet 1 box and 1 map folder
The Ernst Thedore Stuhr Papers document Stuhr's research and writing on medicinal plants and the pharmacy profession. Stuhr served on the faculty of the Oregon State College School of Pharmacy from 1927 to 1944.
Biographical Note:
Ernst Thedore Stuhr was born in 1900. He received a B.S. from the University of Nebraska in 1925 and an M.S. from the University of Florida in 1927. Stuhr served on the faculty of the Oregon State College (OSC) School of Pharmacy from 1927 to 1944 as Assistant Professor of Pharmacy (1927-1930) and Associate Professor (1930-1944) of Pharmacology and Pharmacognosy. His major area of research, medicinal plants, was reflected in the many articles that he wrote for scholarly and trade journals. In 1944, Stuhr resigned from OSC to take a position with Frank Nau Manufacturing Chemists in Portland, Oregon. He was a member of several scientific, honorary and professional societies. Stuhr died on February 12, 1980.
Personal files include personal data and a response prepared by Stuhr and others to an AAUP report on William Jasper Kerr. KOAC radio talks cover a wide range of topics intended for a lay audience. Publications and papers include journal reprints; copies of Stuhr's book, Manual of Pacific Coast Drug Plants; and copies of papers presented at meetings. Series four includes conference proceedings and programs.
Organized into four series, most of which are arranged chronologically. Series include I. Personal Files; II. KOAC Radio Program Talks; III. Publications and Papers; and IV. Conferences.
Colection is open for research.
College of Pharmacy Records (RG 105) and Photographic Collection (P 166); Memorabilia Collection - Pharmacy, School of.
Kerr, William Jasper, 1863-1947
Manual of Pacific coast drug plants
KOAC (Radio station: Corvallis, Or.); Oregon State College. School of Pharmacy.
Pharmacognosy--Oregon.; Pharmacy colleges--Oregon--Corvallis.; Pharmacy--Research--Oregon.; Pharmacy--Study and teaching (Higher)--Oregon--Corvallis.; Botany, Medical.; Botany--Pacific Coast (North America)
Science; Medicine and Health; Colleges and Universities; Oregon; Maps
- Personal Files, 1933-1947; Series I
  - Personal data, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Answer to AAUP report on William Jasper Kerr, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Plant Science Seminar (American Pharmaceutical Assn.) Portland, July-August 1935 (Box 1)
  - S.B. Penick & Co., price list and manual, April 1947 (Box 1)
- KOAC Radio Program Talks, 1936-1942; Series II
  - The Pharmacist's Function in Medical Care, Adolph Ziefle, April 9, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Development and Advances in Pharmaceutical Education, February 10, 1939 (Box 1)
  - The Study of Pharmacy as a Foundation for a Scientific Career, March 10, 1939 (Box 1)
  - The Education of a Pharmacist, April 7, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Narcotic Drug Regulations, May 4, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Exploring Medicinal Plants, June 15, 1939 (Box 1)
  - The Services of the Druggist to the Community, October 19, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Research and Its Applications, December 14, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Accomplishments Through Research, January 25, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Developments in the Realm of Pharmacy, March 21, 1940 (Box 1)
  - First Aid Week, May 16, 1940 (Box 1)
  - National Pharmacy Week, October 24, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Modern Pharmacy, December 19, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Industrial Importance of Medicinal Plants, January 23, 1941 (Box 1)
  - The Sources of Drugs, March 20, 1941 (Box 1)
  - The Collection of Drugs, May 15, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Your Druggist, L.C. Britt and Stuhr, Nov 25, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Graduate Study & Research in the School of Pharmacy, May 14, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Pharmacy in War Time, Oct 19-21, 1942 (Box 1)
    roundtable discussion
  - Services to the State and Nation, School of Pharmacy, undated (Box 1)
  - The Evolution of Drugs, undated (Box 1)
- Publications and Papers, 1928-1956; Series III
  - Manual of Pacific Coast Drug Plants, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Published Articles
    - Medicinal Plants of Florida, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Medicinal Trees of the United States, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Oregon Drug Plants, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Preservation and Storage of Biologicals, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Exploring Economic Plants, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Some Pharmacological and Bactericidal Properties of Umbellulone, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Drugs and Bugs, 1935 (Box 1)
    - The Potency of Oregon Digitalis, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Foresight in Professional Pharmacy, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Some First Aid Principles With Useful Suggestions for Emergencies, 1935 (Box 1)
    - First Aid, (same as preceding article), circa 1935 (Box 1)
    - A Toxicological Study of the Cutaneous Secretions of the Salamander, Triturus Torosus, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Commercial Drug Plantings in Oregon, 1936 (Box 1)
    - The Education of a Pharmacist, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Survey of Regulations and Educational Requirements of Pharmacy in Certain Foreign Countries, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Pentobarbital Sodium as an Anesthetic for Minks, 1941 (Box 1)
    - Therapeutic Interpretation of New Drugs of U.S.P. XII, 1941 (Box 1)
    - Assay of Oregon Ergot, 1943 (Box 1)
    - An Investigation of the Root-Bark of Fatsia Horrida, 1944 (Box 1)
    - The Distribution, Abundance and Uses of Wild Drug Plants in Oregon and Southern California, 1947 (Box 1)
    - A History of Old Oregon Drug Laws, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Papers and Miscellaneous Writings, 1929-1955 (Box 1)
  - Map, Botanical Drug Map of the World, 1934 (Map-case *)
- Conferences, 1948-1954; Series IV
  - Program, Oregon State Pharmaceutical Association, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Proceedings, American Association of Colleges of Pharmacy and the National Association of Boards of Pharmacy, District 7 Joint Conference, 1953-1954 (Box 1)